RESUME

Nasir Uddin Majumder

Experienced in Telecom, Mobile Financial Service and Fintech Industry with Innovative Team building capacity, 36o-degree Leadership style, winning mindset, business turnarounds and strengthening leadership positions of organisations with holistic approach and expert in Smooth Execution, Target Accomplishment & Administrative Capability.

I have learned and groomed in Market Leading organizations like Grameenphone Ltd. And bKash. I am suitable for any placement related to Company's Sales and Distribution starting from the Field to the edge of Strategy.



nasiruddin.majumder@gmail.com +880 171 1505 125

Flat-C-6, House # 207. Road # 10/A, West Dhnamondi,
Dhaka-1205, Bangladesh

SOCIAL MEDIA



https://www.linkedin.com/in/nasir-uddin-majumder-94528570/



@Nasiruddin Majumder

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Business Management (Major in Marketing)

Bangalore University, India *Awarded- 1995-2000*

H.S.C - Science Comilla Board-1993

Comilla Victoria Govt. Collage, Cumilla Result: First Division (65.5%)

SSC - Science - Comilla Board- 1991

Comilla Zilla School, Cumilla Result: First Division (72.2%)

SKILLS

Retail and Wholesale Trade Management

Strategic Planning

Retail Sales

Financial Product / Service Marketing

Process Development

Sales Operations

Business Development

Self-motivation

Team Leadership

Presentation Skill

Data Analysis

Decision Making

Time Management

Customer Relations

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Director- Sales Operations, Distribution Sales

UCB Fintech Company Ltd

https://www.upaybd.com/

2020-Present

- Lead the National Sales Operations for the most fastest growing Mobile Financial Service in Bangladesh.
- Track and Report the total growth and opportunities.
- Performance monitoring for the total Sales Organization.
- Compliance Management
- Training and Development
- Prepare monthly, quarterly and annual Sales forecasts.
- Process Development for the whole Organization.

Head of Operations (2018-2020)

Circle FinTech Ltd (https://www.circlefintech.com/)

- Develop and Implement Effective Sales Strategies
- Lead nationwide Sales team members to achieve Sales targets.
- New Business Development
- Campaign Management.
- Compliance Management
- Training and Development
- Prepare monthly, quarterly and annual Sales forecasts

Regional Sales Manager - Khulna (2016-2018)

Mobility I Tap Pay (BD) Ltd (www.tapnpay.com.bd)

- Responsible for all Commercial related activities of Khulna Region.
- Ensure that Regional team is well aligned with the Retail & Wholesale strategy
- Ensure team motivation to reach common goals / target.
- Active involvement in handling critical business discussion with various channel partners, owners of distribution houses and other key / strategic stakeholders
- Assist Area managers to prepare Distributor KPI, monitor and follow up.

Manager - Sales Training & Development (2014-2015)

bKash Ltd. (https://www.bkash.com/)

- Need Assessment of Training Requirement of all stake holders of Sales & Distribution including own employee, Distribution field force as well as Agents.
- Design and implementation of right learning strategy for the sales force.
- Facilitate soft-skill training on Leadership, Sales, AML CFT, TOT programs.

TECHNICAL SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS

Market Share Growth of Grameenphone in Chittagong Region

2002 - 2005

Magnificently improved the Service Standard Quality of Chittagong Sales Centre that has impacted a positive growth in Market Share of Grameenphone Ltd in Chittagong

Distribution Restructure Project of Grameenphone 2006

Successfully implemented Distribution Restructure Project of Grameenphone Ltd to cater new era challenges of Telecom

Implementation of "SAMURAI" 2009

The first ever Comprehensive Field Force Development Program in Bangladesh for GP's third Party Distributor's Field Force that has sustainably established dominance in the market

180% Revenue Growth of Chittagong Area for bKash Ltd.

2013

Aggressively penetrated market for bKash Ltd that has resulted into 180% Revenue growth within the period of one-year span (2013)

Implementation of Retailer and AML/CFT Training Program for bKash

2013 -2014

Designed, Launched and Rolled out Retailer Training Program and AML/CFT Training Program for Channel in bKash

Roll out Strategy of Circle FinTech Ltd. 2019

Innovative Channel introduction for Modern Financial Service Distribution model in the most vibrant Fintech Start-up in Bangladesh.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

English

Advanced

Bengali

Native Speaker

Hindi and Urdu

Beginner

Sales Manager - Chittagong Area (2012-2013)

bKash Ltd. (https://www.bkash.com/)

- Sales: To attain Monthly / Quarterly / Yearly Sales Target
- Implementation of Distribution Roll out and Retail Channel Activities.
- Planning: Develop right distribution set-up to optimize availability of products in the area.
- Pull and Mobilize all necessary resources to attain business objective.
- Develop and manage the operation of third party distribution channels according bKash suggested guidelines.
- Develop long term business relationship with key channel partners
- Reporting: Manage regular and on demand (Weekly, Monthly and/or Ad-hoc)
- People management: Ensure proper development of team members through on the job training,

Senior Executive, Distribution Know How Management (2009 -2012)

Grameenphone Ltd. (https://www.grameenphone.com/)

- Design & Roll out of Development & Training programs for Grameenphone employees, third party and alternate channels.
- Develop, Implement & Monitor the relevant channels of Grameenphone's distribution system.
- Develop & implement efficiency enhancing tools through process analysis and improvement.

Deputy Manager, Distribution Compliance (2006 – 2009)

Grameenphone Ltd. (https://www.grameenphone.com/)

- Sales related Process Development & Process re-engineering, & Contract development.
- Lead & Motivated team comprised of three & also to manage Legal & Regulatory requirements for Sales team.
- Translate KPI in to action for Wholesaler. Implementation of Risk Management Framework by developing the Strategy & Sustainable Process.
- Channel Management & Support to Wholesale Operations.
- Mid-level Leadership Role to achieving Compliance, Sales, Revenue, Channel Expansion, Manage external 3rd party issues, & Market Growth objectives.

Officer, Distribution (2002 - 2006)

Grameenphone Ltd. (https://www.grameenphone.com/)

- Set targets for Channel partners, Lead the Wholesaler's Sales team and Supervise them in achieving the target.
- Coordinate, Monitor and Control the performance of existing Telecom Wholesale partners
- Profiling / merchandising the existing & new point of Sales
- Actively involvement in handling critical business discussion with various channel partners, owners of wholesale points and other key/strategic stakeholders

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father's Name: Late Joynal Abedin Majumder, Ex-Lawyer, Comilla Bar

Mother's Name: Hosne Ara, Ex-Senior Teacher, Shoilorani Girl's High School, Comilla.

Date of Birth: 01 / 02 / 1977

Marital Status: Married

Nationality: Bangladeshi

Religion: Islam

REFERECE



Nagad
Chief Commercial Officer
+880 181 9210448
sadat.a.ahmad@gmail.com

Relationship : Ex Supervisor

